Andrei Tuta

http://www.github.com/andreituta Mobile: +40725565620

## Career Profile

A passionate Software Developer with extensive and diversified experience in developing mobile applications, websites, web applications and offering administration services for local businesses.

Knowledge of product-life-cycle management, business development and leading cross-functional teams was gained while managing various other projects and business ideas, focusing on understanding existing and emerging technologies, Software as a Service (SaaS), while minimizing their cost and administering workload.

# **EDUCATION**

• Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

 $B.Sc.\ in\ Computer\ Science\ -\ Data\ Analysis. Machine\ Learning\ and\ Database\ administration$ 

2015 - 2018

• Universidad de Alcala

Alcala de Henares, Spain

Email: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Erasmus semester in Spain

Jan - Jun 2017

#### Professional experience

• URJ 6 Points Sci-tech

Byfield, MA

Counselor/Specialist

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

- Counselor: Camp counselor, tasked with managing and leading activities.
- **Programming assistant**: Helping instructors with running the Programming and Coding workshop, focused on teaching programming in Processing for developing their own projects.
- Workshop Instructor: Running my own workshop, in which participants learned the basic syntax of HTML, CSS, JS and the logic behind coding a virtual Monopoly game.
- Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Assistant

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Java demonstrator: Helped groups of students during their laboratory sessions. Tasks involved explaining concepts and helping with debugging their projects.
- Innovation Fest Mentor: Managed and helped two teams of students with the technical development, planning and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest.

• Oracle Romania Bucharest, RO

 $Junior\ Database\ Administrator$ 

Jun - Sep 2017

- Oracle DBA training: Part of the internship consisted of a training similar to a complete DBA course. During this training, topics such as basic administration, back-up, recovery and automation were covered
- Administrator: After the training was completed, I completely installed and automated two separate databases to execute all the required procedures.

#### • Logika IT Solutions

Bucharest, RO

 $Junior\ Database\ Administrator$ 

Jun - Aug 2016

• **Internship**: Worked in a team of 4 people managing the databases of multiple clients. Other responsibilities included writing reports and suggestions on ways to improve the work-flow and diminish cost.

#### Programming Skills

• Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Kotlin, SQL Technologies: AWS, React, Android Studio, MongoDB

## EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

#### • Outward Mobility Ambassador, BCU CEBE

Jan - Jun 2018

Recruiting students for international programs and social media development

## • President, BCU RoSoc

2016 - 2018

Event planning, budgeting & team management

• Secretary, Rotaract Club Birmingham

2015 - 2017

Event planning, PR & note-taking